<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "SS7_Stack_User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]>

<chapter id="introduction">

	<title>Introduction to &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;</title>
	<para>
  Abstract Syntax Notation One (ASN.1) is the standard for describing data structures in telecommunication and computer networking world. ASN.1 provides a set of formal rules for describing the structure of objects. The specification describes abstract objects that are independent of machine-specific encoding techniques.
	</para>
	<para>
  ASN defined data can be encoded using one of these encoding rules:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Basic Encoding Rules (BER)</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Canonical Encoding Rules (CER)</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Distinguished Encoding Rules (DER)</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>XML Encoding Rules (XER)</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Packed Encoding Rules (PER)</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Generic String Encoding Rules (GSER)</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
  ASN.1, together with specific ASN.1 encoding rules, facilitates the exchange of structured data between application programs over networks by describing data structures in a way that is independent of machine architecture and implementation language.
	</para>
	<para>
  ASN encoded data looks logically as follows:
	</para>
  <figure>
    <title>ASN encoding logical overview</title>
    <mediaobject id="asn_encoding">
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="300px" align="center"
          fileref="images/asn-general-encoding.png" format="PNG" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
	<para>Encoded data structure contains three elements:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tag</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Unique value, which identifies the type of data.
        </para>
        <para>
        Tag carries some additional info (such as the complexity and context indicators). The actual Tag value is unique for a single ASN definition (aside from some basic tag values which are defined in the ASN specification).
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Length</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Indicates the length of the current data structure.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payload</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Depending on the definition, this can be a simple value (like an integer), or it can carry another ASN encoded data structure.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

</chapter>
